Guide to the Nancy Grey Osterud papers, 1856-1983.
Osterud, Nancy Grey papers, 1856-1983.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nancy Grey Osterud papers, 1856-1983.
4985
Nancy Grey Osterud.
2.9 cubic ft.
Interviews, diaries, a notebook, and autograph book, photographs, tintypes, pocket almanacs, audiocassettes, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating to the Historian in Residence Program.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Participant in the Historian in Residence Program, 1981-1983
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers relating to the Historian in Residence Program, including Osterud's dissertation and other writings using research material consisting of contemporary oral history interviews with people in the Maine, New York area, and diaries of George Riley (1865-1889) and his Accessor's Books (1887-1889); Judge Hiram Riley diaries (1876-1894) including a notebook for the Ancient Order of Grand Templars Lodge #495; Vernon A. Davy diaries (1889-1897); Chauncy F. McIntyre diaries (1856-1887); Dana Bicknell diary (1870); Mertie Whittemore diaries (1894-1901); Bostwick family ledgers; Alice Johnson autograph book; Maine Fire Company constitution and by-laws (1922); Theodore T. Lawton diaries (1868-1922); and miscellaneous documents, including an 1851 contract to go to the California gold fields. Includes photographs, tintypes, pocket almanacs, and audicassettes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Osterud, Nancy Grey.; Bicknell, Dana.; Bostwick family.; Davy, Vernon A.; Johnson, Alice; Lawton, Theodore T.; McIntyre, Chauncy F.; Riley, Hiram.; Whittemore, Mertie.; Ancient Order of Grand Templars (Maine, N.Y.); Maine Fire Company (Maine, N.Y.); Riley, George.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Maine.; Fire departments--New York (State)--Maine.
Places:
Maine (N.Y.: Town)--Social life and customs.; Maine (N.Y.: Town)--History.; California--Gold discoveries.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers relating to the HIR program and Grey Osterud including a copy of her dissertation and other writings using these materials. (Box 1)
- 64 folders of Oral History transcriptions and extracts from Diaries. (Box 1)
- 6 Diaries. (Box 1)
- George W. Riley, d. Jan. 30, 1890, Diaries, 1865-1889; Accessor's Books, 1887-1889. (Box 2)
- Judson Hiram Riley, [son of Geo. W.], Diaries, 1876-1885, 1887-1894, 1897; Notebook, Ancient Order of Grand Templars, Lodge #495, 1881-1882. (Box 2)
- 1 folder of misc. documents including an 1851 contract to go to the California gold fields, 1851-1906. (Box 2)
- Vernon A. Davey, Arbutus, Diaries, 1889-1897. (Box 2)
- Chancy F. McIntyre, Diaries, 1856, 1875, 1878, 1883-1884, 1886-1887. (Box 2)
- Dana Bicknell, Diary. 1870 and some loose items. (Box 2)
- Miss Mertie Whittemore, Union Center, Diaries, 1894, 1897-1989, 1901. (Box 2)
- Unidentified woman, Diaries, 1895, 1919-1920, [possibly Miss Whittmore]. (Box 2)
- Bostwick Family, Owego, 4 Ledgers re: shoemaking, sheep and wool trade and etc. (Box 2)
- Alice Johnson, Autograph book, 1880s. (Box 2)
- Maine Fire Company #1, Constitution and By-Laws, 1922. (Box 2)
- Hazeltine's Pocket-book Almanac for 1885, 1 1/4" x 2". (Box 2)
- 1 tintype, 2 photographs. (Box 2)
- Theo. T. Lawton, Diaries, 1868-1922 and misc. papers. (Box 3-4)
- 47 cassettes of Oral History, see Box 1 for transcriptions. (Box 5)